Guide to the Bradshaw Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Bradshaw family papers
1886-1939
MS 1234
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.75
(2 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence, memorabilia, financial and legal papers, and photographs which chronicle the academic careers and brief marriage of Francis and Margaret Bradshaw and the career of their daughter, Frances Bradshaw Blanshard.
Bradshaw family
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Brand and Roberta Blanshard, 1980. Additional papers are the gift of Roberta Yerkes Blanshard, 1990.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Bradshaw Family Papers consist of correspondence, memorabilia, financial and legal papers, and photographs which chronicle the academic careers and brief marriage of Francis and Margaret Bradshaw and the career of their daughter Frances Bradshaw Blanshard. Additional Bradshaw material, including correspondence between Margaret Bradshaw and her son-in-law Brand Blanshard and papers of Frances Bradshaw Blanshard, can be found in the Brand Blanshard Papers. Brand and Roberta Yerkes Blanshard donated the papers between 1980 and 1990.
Biographical / Historical
Margaret Rooker Bradshaw was born in Delaware County, Missouri, on March 8, 1866. She was the daughter of John and Nancy Hampton Rooker. She received a B.A. degree from Hardin College. In 1890 she married Francis Elmer Bradshaw. The young married couple both attended Vanderbilt University where they each earned M.A. degrees in 1893.
The Bradshaws did graduate work at Yale University from 1893 to 1894. Francis Bradshaw accepted a teaching position at Vanderbilt for the following year. Their daughter Frances was born in 1895, and in October of that year Francis Bradshaw died of typhoid. Left a widow with an infant daughter, Margaret Bradshaw accepted a position as a teacher at Brookfield College where she stayed until 1900. She returned to Yale in 1900 to continue her graduate work and earned her Ph.D. in 1902.
In 1902 Margaret Bradshaw was offered a position as instructor in English at Smith College. She was promoted to the rank of associate professor in 1912 and continued teaching until she suffered a stroke in 1930. She died on September 27, 1946 in Swarthmore, Pennsylvania, where her daughter Frances Blanshard had lived when she was Swarthmore College's dean of women.
Families; Husband and wife; Students; Blanshard, Frances Bradshaw, 1895-1966; Bradshaw, Francis Elmer, d. 1895; Bradshaw, Margaret Rooker; Smith College -- Faculty; Yale University -- Students
- Inventory
  - Financial and legal papers, 1889-1902, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Personal Correspondence
    - General, 1890-1895 April (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - General, 1895 May-1929, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Between Francis E. Bradshaw and Margaret Rooker Bradshaw, 1894 June (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Between Francis E. Bradshaw and Margaret Rooker Bradshaw, 1894 July (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Between Francis E. Bradshaw and Margaret Rooker Bradshaw, 1895 April (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Between Francis E. Bradshaw and Margaret Rooker Bradshaw, 1895 May 1-14 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Between Francis E. Bradshaw and Margaret Rooker Bradshaw, 1895 May 15-28, September (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Letters of condolence to Margaret Rooker Bradshaw, 1895 October-November (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - From Frances Bradshaw Blanshard, 1906, 1912 April-June (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - From Frances Bradshaw Blanshard, 1919 June-December (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - From Frances Bradshaw Blanshard, 1920 January-March (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - From Frances Bradshaw Blanshard, 1920 April-June (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - From Frances Bradshaw Blanshard, 1924-1929 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - From Frances Bradshaw Blanshard, 1938 August-October (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - From Frances Bradshaw Blanshard, 1938 November-December (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - From Frances Bradshaw Blanshard, 1939 January-March (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - From Frances Bradshaw Blanshard, 1939 April-August (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Photographs (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Professional papers
    - Francis E. Bradshaw, 1886-1892 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Francis E. Bradshaw, 1894-1895, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Margaret Rooker Bradshaw, 1887-1906, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)